Okay, so in this video
we're going to cover
the PIMBOC processes for scope management.
And this is all taken from PIMBOC version
6.
So the processes, then, there are six
processes in scope management altogether.
So in planning, there's four processes.
In monitoring controlling, there are two.
Now, just like all of the other processes,
right, from scope management actually all
the way down, when you look
at the knowledge areas, the
very first process, is always
plan something management.
So in this case, the very first process
will be plan scope management.
And remember in plan
scope management, you're
going to be creating the
scope management plan.
So in the old PIMBOC 6 terminology,
we would say that the scope management
plan is actually an output of plan scope
management.
So the scope management plan then remember
is an artifact that is documenting how
we're going to develop the scope and
there's a separate video in more details
in the kind of information that it
contains but that is an artifact that is
created as part of plan scope management
and the artifact then in this case is
considered an output and any artifact that
you're creating from any process is
loosely considered an output right the old
PMI terminology Pimbox 6, terminology,
it would be considered an output.
Now, that's the very first process in any
of the knowledge areas.
The very first process is to create the
plan, right?
Plan how we're going to, you know,
do this particular knowledge area.
So in this case, how are we going to
develop the scope?
Now, this next process then is collect
requirements.
We need some requirements in order to
understand what the customer wants,
in order to be able to scope out the
project.
So that's this process here, collect
requirements.
And the artifact that's created or the
output, if you like, of collect
requirements, is the requirements
documentation and the requirements
traceability matrix, both of which are
going to be covered in a future video.
Then once we've started
collecting some requirements,
then we can start defining
the scope of the project.
So that's the other process here,
define scope.
And that's where we're going to create the
scope statement.
So the scope statement is considered the
output of defined scope.
It's an artifact that's created as part of
defined scope.
And then we're going to create the work
breakdown structure.
Create WBS.
WBS stands for the work breakdown
structure.
And the work breakdown
structure, the graphical
hierarchy of all the work
that needs to be done.
And one of the key artifacts that's
created is the scope baseline.
And the scope baseline is made up of the
work breakdown structure, as well as
something called the work breakdown
structure dictionary and the scope
statement, which is created from the
defined scope process, and again,
we've got videos on, or detailed videos on
each of these.
So that's under planning.
Under the monitoring
controlling side, we have
something, we have a
process called validate scope.
And validate scope is the customer's
acceptance of the deliverable.
So it's a customer that's accepting the
deliverable.
So as a team, we are going to implement
the work.
We're first going to plan the work,
then we're going to implement the work,
and then we're going to test the work,
right, which is quality control.
Once we've tested it, now the customer
needs to test and sign off.
And the customer's
testing and signing off on
the deliverable is
known as validate scope.
And then control scope
is something that as a
project manager you're
doing throughout your project.
You're controlling the scope of the
project, right?
You're making sure
that we are doing all the
work necessary and
only the work necessary.
We're not doing anything additional.
We're trying to prevent scope creep and
gold plating, remember?
How are we controlling the scope of the
project?
By going through a
change control, by having
a proper change control process in place.
Okay?
So these are the six processes then in
scope management.
And so we're going to be
covering going through the
details of each of these
in our subsequent videos.